CONTACT

Address: Flat Number 5, Elizabeth Place,

High Wycombe, HP12 4AE **Phone**: +44 7448314537

Email: vikas_mullana@yahoo.com

SKILLS

- Java, Python, Typescript, Dataweave
- Frameworks: Spring, Angular, Struts, JSF, Flask
- ORM: Hibernate
- AWS RDS, DynamoDB, ECS, SNS
- Microservices
- Rest API, SOAP
- MuleSoft
- Relational DB: MySQL, Oracle DB
- Non-Relational DB Amazon DynamoDB
- Cache Redis In-memory DB
- HTML 5, CSS 3
- Cucumber, Rest-Assured
- JMeter
- Maven
- Git, SVN
- Jenkins
- Jira, Rally
- Tableau, PowerBI

CERTIFICATIONS

- Oracle Certified Java Professional
- Google Associate Cloud Engineer
- Google Certified TensorFlow Developer
- MuleSoft Certified Developer
- MuleSoft Certified Platform Architect
- MuleSoft Certified Integration Architect

Vikas Puri

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution minded Professional with over 13 years of experience seeking suitable Job Opportunity in Java or Full-Stack technologies.

I am an experienced professional with **enriched skills in Full-Stack development, Integration Development and Architecture**. I hold experience in domains like Automotive, Banking, and Healthcare. I am Oracle Certified Java professional. I am always interested to expand my knowledge thus also worked in an Integration area using MuleSoft and worked on GenAl area using Python, Google Gemini API's.

WORK HISTORY

Java Lead and Developer

02/2023 - Present

Deloitte - London, United Kingdom

Worked as Java Lead and Developer for one of the global leading automotive client.

- Designed high level architecture of application
- Involved in the requirement gathering and doing analysis.
- Lead a team of 5 members
- Involved in developing microservices and used databases as Amazon RDS and Dynamo DB.
- Actively involved in doing code review of the team members
- Involved in setting up of Jenkins pipeline
- Participate in sprint ceremonies to decompose stories into tasks and provide estimates.

Tech Stack: Spring Boot, Java 8, Maven, Docker, AWS RDS, AWS Dynamo DB, AWS ECS, AWS SNS, Mockito

Python Developer

Deloitte - London, United Kingdom

Worked as Python Developer to perform POC on the video analytics tool.

- Designed high level architecture of the application.
- Designed and developing application to upload videos to Google Cloud.
- Develop GenAl application to perform video analysis (like we can ask summary, genre and other details) of the uploaded video.

Tech Stack: Python 3.12, Flask, Angular 18, Google Cloud - Object Storage, Google Compute Engine.

Integration Architect

02/2022 - 01/2023

Deloitte - London, United Kingdom

Worked as Integration architect for one of the global leading automotive clients.

- Involved in the requirement gathering and doing analysis
- Designed high level architecture of application using API Led connectivity approach
- Involved in developing designing and development of the code
- Actively involved in doing code review of the team members
- Involved in setting up of Jenkins pipeline

Tech Stack: MuleSoft 4.4, Lucid Chart, Dataweave, GCP Pub-Sub.

Associate Lead

07/2014 - 12/2019

Nagarro Software Pvt. Ltd. - Gurugram, India

Worked as Associate Lead for the Top most Automobile company in Germany.

- Participated in deciding the technical approaches.
- Involved in the requirement gathering and doing the POC for the same.
- Involved in the coding of front end using Angular 4, HTML 5 and CSS 3.
- Involved in the coding of backend using Java, Hibernate, Spring.
- Involved in developing the Jenkins pipeline.
- Actively involved in the code reviews.
- Introduced the Flyway for maintaining the database of different environments in sync.
- Introduced caching using Redis.
- Implemented Stored Procedures, Triggers and views.

IT Engineer - SI

05/2012 - 06/2014

CMC Limited - Noida, India

Worked as IT engineer for the product of one the Indian Consulting services.

- Prepared high level design documents like ER diagrams, Sequence Diagrams.
- Involved in the development of the application using Java, JSF and Primefaces.
- Involved in writing the queries and stored procedures.
- Involved in improving the performance of the queries.
- Introduced the JMS, so as soon as request raised other systems will be notified.

Software Engineer

10/2010 - 04/2012

NTT Data - Noida, India

Worked as Software Engineer for Leading Hospital chain in the US.

- Involved in the development of the backend code using Java, and Struts.
- Involved in writing the DB Stored Procedures.
- Involved in fixing the bugs.

EDUCATION

Master's in Artificial Intelligence and Robotics: Jan 2020 - Jan 2022, University of Hertfordshire - Hatfield, Hertfordshire, England

Bachelor of Technology: Electronic and Instrumentation Engineering, 06/2008 **Maharishi Markandeshwar Engineering College** - Mullana, Haryana, India